THARUN NOOKALA

SDE 1 @ valmi.io

Frontend Developer

Linked in: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tharun-nookala

iamtharun7799@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://tharunnookala.netlify.app/

OBJECTIVE

Enthusiastic Full Stack Developer with nearly 2.7 years of hands-on experience in crafting and optimizing responsive websites. Currently focused on driving innovation as a Frontend Developer for Valmi.io, where I contribute to develop user interfaces and API integrations for an embedded data platform tailored for eCommerce. Also an intermediate level leetcode problem solver.

E-mail:

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer 1 @ valmi.io

February 2024 - current

Frontend Developer - (0.8 years)

- Contributed significantly to the creation and refinement of key front-end features, including from setting up the app's theme, designing layouts to managing end-to-end user flows.
- Integrated Google Authentication using NextAuth to streamline user login processes, incorporating tokenbased authentication for secure backend access.
- Developed and integrated Shopify OAuth functionality to facilitate seamless access to Shopify stores as part of the product features.
- Engineered custom renderers for JsonForms, enabling dynamic form generation based on Json Schema, enhancing the flexibility and scalability of form management within the application.
- Integrated RESTful APIs to connect with back-end, for creating etl connectors from various sources to destinations, get the data into google-sheets, ensuring smooth data flow and user interactions.
- Used Redux Toolkit for efficient application state management, ensuring a consistent and reliable user experience.
- Implemented RTK Query for streamlined API interaction, optimizing data fetching functionalities and caching strategies.

Systems Engineer @ Infosys

July 2021 - May 2023

Frontend Web Developer - (\sim 2 years)

- Worked on technologies such as JavaScript, React JS, CSS, Material UI for a logistics management system, streamlining Client's supply chain and inventory processes.
- Enabled real-time data visualization by integrating various APIs, allowing users to track logistics metrics, shipment statuses, and inventory levels with up-to-date information.
- Improved the overall usability and functionality of the system by creating responsive web components, including dashboards, Carousel cards, Search bar to fetch data from API and FAQ Component for the obtained designs from Figma by UI team ensuring accessibility across different devices.
- Performed quality assurance tests on various sites to ensure cross browser compatibility and mobile responsiveness.
- Worked with version control systems like Git to manage code and collaborate with other developers.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to ensure seamless integration of front-end and back-end functionality.
- Implemented best practices for SEO and web analytics by implementing lazy loading of images to reduce the load time.
- Familiar with Agile methodologies, Scrum and Jira to effectively manage projects.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, React JS, Next JS, Redux, Redux Toolkit, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS, Material UI/MUI, Shadcn/ui, Git, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Styled Components, Node JS, Express JS.

Miscellaneous: Axios, GitHub, Firebase, Docker, Jest, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Adobe Photoshop.

EDUCATION

QUALIFICATION	SCHOOL/COLLEGE	PERIOD	MARKS/CGPA
SSC	New Vision School, Khammam.	2014-15	9.50
Intermediate (12th)	Narayana Junior College, Hyderabad.	2015-17	963
B.Tech. (Information	Sreenidhi Institute of Science and Technology,	2017-21	7.16
Technology)	Hyderabad.		

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- 1. **Easy Pizza:** An Online Pizza delivery web app where we can order pizza by providing our name, address and phone number and based on only cash-on-delivery. Built using React, Redux, Tailwind CSS. <u>Check here</u>
- 2. **World Wise:** A web app where we can track the places that we visited and add some notes about it. We can locate a position in the map and add/remove a city. Built using React, Context API, use Reducer, CSS. Check here
- 3. **Eat'N-Split:** A fully functional react app similar to *splitwise* where we can split a bill between us and a friend built using React JS functional components and hooks. Styled using Tailwind CSS. Check here
- 4. **Netflix Clone**: A Netflix like app created by React functional components and styled using Tailwind CSS. Database is authenticated using Firebase. Check here
- 5. Online E-Commerce Store (CRWN-Store): An e-commerce store built using React JS functional components and hooks. Styled using SCSS and databases integration was done using firebase. Client-side state management with Redux.
- 6. **React-Tailwind Landing Page:** A beautiful landing page fully responsive developed using React JS and Tailwind CSS. Check here
- 7. **Shopify Bot**: Built a bot which we can add to any Shopify store that enables seamless interaction of owner and customer. Vanilla JavaScript and basic WebSocket server connections are used.

PERSONAL SKILLS AND STRENGTHS

Adaptability and flexibility, Collaborative, Good problem-solving skills, Positive attitude, Team player, Self-taught, Continuous learner.